Guide to the New York University Archives Audiovisual Collection AV
New York University Archives
- Audiovisual Recordings
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, view from V. Olivi open theater, 1987 July 30; AV2229; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2229)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, conversations with Acton and Dr. Brademas, 1987 July 30; AV2230; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2230)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2231; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2231)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, conversations with Acton and Dr. Brademas, 1987 July 30; AV2232; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2232)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, Dr. Brademas' questions, 1987 July 30; AV2233 (Box 58, Item 2233)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2234; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2234)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, Ponte Vecchio, Museo Horne, 1987 July 30; AV2235; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2235)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, I Tatti, Professor Clubb, 1987 July 30; AV2236; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2236)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, Piazza Signoria Della, 1987 July 30; AV2237; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 58, Item 2237)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, stills of photographs, views from hall into garden, 1987 July 30; AV2238; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2238)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, stills (B)-China Pix-Old Villa P. Pix, 1987 July 30; AV2239; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2239)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, stills (C)-old villa before Italian garden, 1987 July 30; AV2240; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2240)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, conversation with Acton on Cina and his house, 1987 July 30; AV2241; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2241)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, views of Cypress Avenue, 1987 July 30; AV2242; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2242)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, interiors, red damask room, "Rape of the Sabinets" above staircase, 1987 July 30; AV2243; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2243)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, grotto room, 1987 July 30; AV2244; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2244)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2245; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2245)
    Related material
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2246; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2246)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2247; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2247)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2248; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2248)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, art on second floor (Madonna in bedroom), Acton in his study, dog, 1987 July 30; AV2249; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2249)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, Acton and Carter Brown, 1987 July 30; AV2250; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2250)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, conversations with Acton and Carter Brown, 1987 July 30; AV2251; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2251)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, conversations facing Carter Brown, 1987 July 30; AV2252; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2252)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, stills (aquarium, Oxford bedroom, front gate from inside villa), 1987 July 30; AV2253; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 59, Item 2253)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, questions (Carter Brown), 1987 July 30; AV2254; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 60, Item 2254)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2255; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 60, Item 2255)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2256; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 60, Item 2256)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2257; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 60, Item 2257)
  - Harold Acton Tape Project: La Pietra, 1987 July 30; AV2258; Approx. 30 minutes (Box 60, Item 2258)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2283 (Box 60, Reel 2283)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2284 (Box 60, Reel 2284)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2285 (Box 61, Reel 2285)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2286 (Box 61, Reel 2286)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2288 (Box 61, Reel 2288)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2287 (Box 61, Reel 2287)
  - 100th Anniversary of the School of Engineering and Science, 1955; AV2289 (Box 61, Reel 2289)
  - Commencement Exercises (tape 1 of 2), 1966 June 8; AV2306; Goldberg, Arthur J. (Box 61, Disc 2306, Quarter inch audio reel 2306)
  - Commencement Exercises (tape 2 of 2), 1966 June 8; AV2307 (Box 61, Disc 2307, Box 123, Quarter inch audio reel 2307)
    The speaker on this reel of the 1966 commencement exercises was George A. Murphy.
    Duration: 3 minutes
  - "Our Happiest Birthday", 1976 July 4; AV2561; Cronkite, Walter (Box 66, Cassette 2561)
  - Highlights in Jazz #16: The Jazz/Latin Jam - Ray Barretto, Ray Bryant, Jon Faddis, Joe Farrell, Joe Beck, Herb Bushler, Jimmy Madison, Mel Lewis, Andrea Brachfeld (Tape 3 of 3), 7 October 1974; AV2572; Kleinsinger, Jack; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2572)
    This recording is labeled Tape 3 of 3. The University Archives does not have Tapes 1 or 2.
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "This tape contains only about 6 minutes of content. As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent, constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies on tighter shots. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts and tape wear, and one instance of tape damage. Occasional mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
    Jazz
  - Highlights in Jazz #17: Salute to Swing! The Music of Ellington, Goodman, Basie and others - Joe Newman, Zoot Sims, Phil Bodner, Bucky Pizzarelli, George Duvivier, Panama Francis, Hank Jones, Maxine Sullivan, David Lee (Tape 1 of 2), 1974-12-16; AV2573; Kleinsinger, Jack; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2573)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies in low lighting. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are frequent mild dropouts, and occasional tape damage and head clogs. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #17: Salute to Swing! The Music of Ellington, Goodman, Basie and others - Joe Newman, Zoot Sims, Phil Bodner, Bucky Pizzarelli, George Duvivier, Panama Francis, Hank Jones, Maxine Sullivan, David Lee (Tape 2 of 2), 1974-12-16; AV2580; Dutton, Shirley; Kleinsinger, Jack; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2580)
    This recording was donated to the University Archives by the Loeb Student Center Program Office in 1982.
    This tape is labeled Tape 2 of 2. The University Archives does not have Tape 1.
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Entirety of tape suffers from a constant control track error. Multiple TBCs were tested to obtain the best capture possible. Content suffers from persistent flagging throughout, as a result of the inherent control track error. Recurring mild tape wear and dropouts throughout. Occasional mild ghosting. Inherent mild audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #18: Big Band Sounds for the Seventies - Bill Watrous and the Manhattan Wildlife Refuge, Dr. Lyn Christie (Tape 1 of 3), 1975-02-10; 2574; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2574)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Tranfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies in low lighting. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts and tape damage. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Mild audio distortion and buzz is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #18: Big Band Sounds for the Seventies - Bill Watrous and the Manhattan Wildlife Refuge, Dr. Lyn Christie (Tape 2 of 3), 1975-02-10; AV2575 (Box 155, Reel 2575)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies in low lighting. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts and tape damage. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Mild audio distortion and buzz is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #18: Big Band Sounds for the Seventies - Bill Watrous and the Manhattan Wildlife Refuge, Dr. Lyn Christie (Tape 3 of 3), 1975-02-10; AV2576 (Box 155, Reel 2576)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Only about half the tape has content recorded on it. As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent, constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies on tighter shots. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are frequent mild dropouts, and occasional mild tape damage. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording. Audio inherently cuts out for final 30 seconds of content."
  - Highlights in Jazz #20: The Great Ellington Reunion / Soprano Summit - Al Hibbler, Brooks Kerr, Russell Procope, Sonny Greer, Francis Williams, Bob Wilber, Ken Davern, George Duvivier, Ken Rosengarden, Marty Grosz, Aaron Bell, Peter Dean (Tape 1 of 3), 1975-04-21; AV2577; Kleinsinger, Jack; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2577)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers. Mild image jitter throughout. A persistent skew error exists during the first 40 seconds. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts and tape wear. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #20: The Great Ellington Reunion / Soprano Summit - Al Hibbler, Brooks Kerr, Russell Procope, Sonny Greer, Francis Williams, Bob Wilber, Ken Davern, George Duvivier, Ken Rosengarden, Marty Grosz, Aaron Bell, Peter Dean (Tape 2 of 3), 1975-04-21; AV2578; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2578)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Entirety of tape suffers from a constant control track error. Multiple TBCs were tested to obtain the best capture possible. Content suffers from persistent flagging and image jitter throughout, as a result of the inherent control track error. Aside from these anomalies, there is recurring mild tape wear and dropouts, and occasional mild tape damage. Momentary severe sync errors occur twice."
  - Highlights in Jazz #20: The Great Ellington Reunion / Soprano Summit - Al Hibbler, Brooks Kerr, Russell Procope, Sonny Greer, Francis Williams, Bob Wilber, Ken Davern, George Duvivier, Ken Rosengarden, Marty Grosz, Aaron Bell, Peter Dean (Tape 3 of 3), 1975-04-21 (Box 155, Reel AV2579)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Only about half the tape has content recorded on it. As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent, constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies on tighter shots. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are frequent mild dropouts, and occasional mild tape damage. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Highlights in Jazz #15: Billie Holiday Remembered - Bennie Morton, Doc Cheatham, Earle Warren, Buddy Tate, George Wein, Panama Francis, George Duvivier, Ruth Brisbane, Haywood Henry (Tape 1 of 2), 17 June; AV2581; Kleinsinger, Jack; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2581)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies in low lighting. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts, and occasional tape damage and tape wear. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
    Jazz; Holiday, Billie, 1915-1959
  - Highlights in Jazz #15: Billie Holiday Remembered - Bennie Morton, Doc Cheatham, Earle Warren, Buddy Tate, George Wein, Panama Francis, George Duvivier, Ruth Brisbane, Haywood Henry (Tape 2 of 2), 1974-06-17; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2582)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the performers, but intensifies in low lighting. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts, and occasional tape wear. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Luma is adjusted to mitigate clipping from glare. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Great Speakers Series 1974 #1: Ramsey Clark, 1974-02-21; AV2894; Clark, Ramsey, 1927-; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 155, Reel 2894, Box 75, Reel 2895)
    These recordings are related to RG 12.2.5, Records of the Loeb Student Center.
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2894: "Content plays well throughout. A persistent mild skew error is visible on podium in bottom third of frame. Occasional mild dropouts and tape wear. A couple instances of inherent audio errors occur, and there is loud hiss throughout. Mild head switch error visible in underscan."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV2895: "Content exists on only about 25 minutes of tape. The program plays well throughout, though there is a mild skew error that effects a portion of the image in the bottom third of the frame. No other major errors detected during capture."
  - Great Speakers Series 1974 #2: Jimmy Breslin, 1974-02-28; AV2896; Breslin, Jimmy; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2896)
    This recording is related to RG 12.2.5, Records of the Loeb Student Center.
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Content is almost entirely a static shot of Jimmy Breslin speaking at a podium, and it plays with very little error. The TBC used introduces a mild skew error in bottom third of frame, but was deemed to yield the best image among a number of TBCs. Mild ghosting throughout. Audio buzzing throughout, which intensifies when Breslin stops for audience questions. Mild head switch error visible throughout."
  - Great Speakers Series 1974 #4: Dick Cavett, 1974-03-13; AV2897; Cavett, Dick; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2897)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Content is almost entirely a static shot of Dick Cavett speaking at a podium. A persistent skew error affecting the bottom third of the frame is visible throughout. Much of the content suffers from moderate to severe flagging. Severe inherent audio distortion affects the fist 4 or 5 minutes of content, but is resolved following that. Moderate head switch error visible throughout. Content ends abruptly at tail."
  - Great Speakers Series II #1: Gloria Steinem / Jane Galvin-Lewis (Tape 2 of 2), 17 October 1974; AV2898; Steinem, Gloria; Galvin-Lewis, Jane; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2898)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Entirety of tape suffers from a constant control track error. Multiple TBCs were tested to obtain the best capture possible. Content suffers from persistent flagging and image jitter throughout, as a result of the inherent control track error. Aside from these anomalies, there is recurring mild tape wear and dropouts throughout. Occasional flash photography results in luma clipping and momentarily affects image stability."
  - Great Speakers Series 1974 #5: George McGovern, 1974-03-21; AV2899; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; 1 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2899)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes: "Content exists on only on about 7 minutes of tape, featuring the end of a Q+A with George McGovern. Moderate image jitter affects content throughout. This error is less problematic than errors presented by other TBCs for this tape. Occasional dropouts and mild tape wear throughout. Head switch error visible throughout. Inherent loss of audio at end of presentation."
  - Great Speakers Series II #2: Ralph Nader, 1974-10-24; AV2900; Nader, Ralph; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2900, Reel 2901)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2900: "Headswitch error in underscan. Severe skew error across top of frame throughout entire frame. Attempted to fix this by trying multiple TBCs and decks, this was the best possible quality. Mild Dropouts throughout."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV2901: "Entirety of tape suffers from a constant control track error. Multiple TBCs were tested to obtain the best capture possible. Content suffers from persistent flagging and image jitter throughout, as a result of the inherent control track error. Aside from these anomalies, there is recurring mild tape wear and dropouts throughout, and occasional mild tape damage. Image is less stable when camera moves to feature audience questions."
  - Great Speakers Series II #4: Sam Ervin, 1974-11; AV2902; Ervin, Sam J. (Sam James), 1896-1985; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2902, Reel 2903)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2902: "Content is primarily a static shot of Senator Ervin speaking at a podium. As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate flagging throughout. This flagging is generally above the speaker. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are occasional mild dropouts and tape wear. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording. Pronounced audio buzzing present during audience Q+A."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV2903: "Content recorded on just several minutes near head of tape. As with other tapes in this collection, there is an inherent constant sync error that is stabilized by time base correction, but ultimately results in moderate to severe flagging throughout. Mild image jitter throughout. Elsewhere, there are frequent mild dropouts, and occasional mild tape damage. Occasional inherent exposure adjustments and mild ghosting. Audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
  - Jazz, the American Invention #4: The Big Band - Thad Jones-Mel Lewis Orchestra, Dee Dee Bridgewater, 1973-10-24; AV2904; Kleinsinger, Jack; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2904, Reel 2905)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2904: "Majority of content features a big band performance directed by Les McCann, with several establishing shots in the beginning. A persistent skew error is present in the bottom half of the frame throughout, with some portions more severe than others. This error was less problematic than errors introduced by other TBCs. Otherwise the content plays well, with one instance of momentary sync error, and one instance of minor tape damage. Occasional ghosting and inherent exposure adjustments throughout. Head switch error visible throughout. Mild audio distortion is inherent to the original recording."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV2905: "Content plays well throughout. A persistent skew error affecting the bottom half of the frame is visible throughout, and contributes to moderate bearding. Mild to moderate ghosting and tube burn visible, especially following swift movement. Mild head switch error visible throughout. Content ends abruptly at tail."
  - Jazz, the American Invention #5: Rhythm & Contemporary Music - Les McCann Quartet, 1973-10-31; AV2906; McCann, Les, 1935-; Kleinsinger, Jack; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 75, Reel 2906, Reel 2907)
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2906: "First few minutes feature a number of establishing shots with occasional inherent edits and crash records. Main portion of content begins around 8 minutes in. Les McCann Ltd performance plays well throughout, with occasional tape damage, flicker, ghosting, and mild tube burn. There are occasional portions that exhibit a very mild skew error, but it doesn't persist throughout the performance. High head switch error visible throughout. Moderate inherent audio distortion throughout, particularly during performance."
    Transfer Technician Notes AV2907: "Content exists on about a third of the tape. Performance plays well throughout, though there is significant inherent audio distortion. Occasional dropouts and mild tape wear, with one instance of tape damage. Occasional mild ghosting. High head switch error visible throughout."
  - Highlights in Jazz #14: Odetta, David Amram, Pepper Adams, Jerry Dodgion, Herb Bushler, Al Harewood, 1974-05-06; cuid656; Kleinsinger, Jack; Amram, David; Odetta, 1930-2008; 2 Half_Inch_Video_Reel (Box 53, Reel 2908, Box 156, Reel 2909)
    This concert took place at the Eisner & Lubin Auditorium at the Loeb Student Center at New York University.
    Original format: 1/2 inch open reel video; Transfer Technician Notes AV2908: "Content plays mostly well throughout. Image jitter persists, especially near beginning and end of tape. Occasional dropouts and mild tape wear throughout, with a couple instances of tape damage. Occasional tracking noise. Head switch error visible throughout. Mild inherent audio distortion. Content is inherently without audio for first minute."